Register of the Henry S. Rowen papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- 2016 Incremental Materials, 1958-2015
  - Department of Defense materials, 1960-2014
    - Long Term Strategy, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 43: 9)
    - "The Old SALT Gang Returns," Wall Street Journal, 1984 November (Box-folder 44: 1-2)
    - U. S. Interests Section (Iraq), 1984 (Box-folder 44: 3)
    - Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) Modernization Task Force, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 44: 4)
    - Arroyo project, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 44: 5)
    - Rowen "Fault Lines" writings, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 44: 6-7)
    - "Fault Lines" research, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 44: 8-9)
    - "Fault Lines in the Warsaw Pact" drafts, 1984 (Box-folder 44: 10)
    - Arms control, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 44: 11)
    - Ditchley Foundation conferences, 1985 February (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - Kissinger book materials, 1985 (Box-folder 45: 2-4)
    - "The Mirrored Image,", 1985 (Box-folder 45: 5-6)
    - Writings, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 45: 7-8, 46: 1)
    - Defense Science Board Task Force, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 46: 2)
    - "Policy Measures to Reduce Warsaw Pact Cohesion,", 1986 April (Box-folder 46: 3)
    - Navy Area-Wide (NAW) talk: "Contingencies and Attack Requirements in the Future,", 1986 June (Box-folder 46: 4)
    - Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) Task Force, 1986 (Box-folder 46: 5)
    - Midgetman, 1986 (Box-folder 46: 6)
    - Strategic Defense Initiative, 1986, 1995 (Box-folder 46: 7)
    - "The Persisting Illusion: Gaining Security Through Arms Agreements,", 1986-1987 (Box-folder 46: 8)
    - Clippings related to nuclear war, 1986-2005 (Box-folder 46: 9)
    - Integrated Long Term Strategy - Senator William Bradley, 1987 (Box-folder 46: 10)
    - Commission on Integrated Long Term Strategy, 1987 (Box-folder 46: 11)
    - Integrated Long Term Strategy, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 47: 1-5, 48: 1-2)
    - Integrated Long Term Strategy - Economics, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 48: 3)
    - Integrated Long Term Strategy - Naval, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 48: 4)
    - Integrated Long Term Strategy - Future Security, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 48: 5)
    - Integrated Long Term Strategy - Nuclear Strategic Defense, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 48: 6)
    - Integrated Long Term Strategy - Mobilization, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - Integrated Long Term Strategy - Arms Control, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 49: 2)
    - Writings, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 49: 3-4)
    - "Anti-Coalition Strategies: Soviet and Western Approaches,", 1988 March 29 (Box-folder 49: 5)
    - Viewgraphs for NAW talk in Washington, 1988 November 16 (Box-folder 49: 6)
    - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1988 (Box-folder 49: 7)
    - Commission on Integrated Long Term Strategy, 1988 (Box-folder 49: 8)
    - Missile proliferation, 1988 (Box-folder 49: 9)
    - Wall Street Journal articles written by Rowen, 1988 (Box-folder 49: 10)
    - Project Bold Stroke, 1989 (Box-folder 49: 11)
    - Ambassador's Residence reception, 1990 January (Box-folder 49: 12)
    - East Asia trip, 1990 February (Box-folder 50: 1-3)
      Includes photographs.
    - Pakistani trip, 1990 June (Box-folder 50: 4)
    - Saudi Arabian visit, 1990 (Box-folder 50: 5)
    - Paris and Tunis visit, 1990 (Box-folder 50: 6)
    - Gulf War clippings, 1990 (Box-folder 50: 7)
    - Gulf War, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 50: 8)
      Also known as Operation Desert Shield or Operation Desert Storm.
    - Livermore Labs visit, 1991 June 28 (Box-folder 50: 9)
    - National Training Center, 1991 July 3 (Box-folder 50: 10)
    - Assistant Secretary of Defense departure, 1991 July (Box-folder 50: 11)
    - Defense Department visit to Egypt and Israel, 1991 (Box-folder 51: 1-2)
    - Defense Policy Board correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 51: 3)
    - "Gulf War Air Power Survey" draft, 1993 April 15 (Box-folder 51: 4)
    - Naval War College war game, 1994 (Box-folder 51: 5)
    - Defense Policy Board, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 51: 6)
    - "Iraq's Post Conflict Reconstruction,", 2003 July 17 (Box-folder 51: 7)
    - Iraqi intelligence article, 2004 February 13 (Box-folder 51: 8)
    - The Princeton Project on National Security, 2006 March (Box-folder 51: 9)
    - "The BMD Threat Analysis Study,", undated (Box-folder 51: 10)
    - Certificate of Retirement, 1991 July 31 (Box 87)
    - Printed matter, 1971-2014 (Boxes 52-57)
      Comprised largely of Pan Heuristics reports written by Rowen and many others. Some prominent titles and series include Moving Toward Life in a Nuclear Armed Crowd?; The Berlin Crises, 1958-1961; Can We Make Nuclear Power Compatible with Limiting the Spread of Nuclear Weapons?, and Persian Gulf Oil and Western Security.
  - Stanford University materials, 1959-2015
    Writings, notes, and printed matter Rowen created and collected as a professor at Stanford University, fellow at the Hoover Institution, and member of the Asia-Pacific Research Center.
    - Nuclear History Project, 1963-1995 (Box-folder 58: 1)
    - Reviews of Rowen's books, 1965-2000 (Box-folder 58: 2)
    - "Natural Gas Technology Task Force for the Technical Advisory Committee of the National Gas Survey by the Federal Power Commission,", 1973 April 1 (Box-folder 58: 3)
    - "How Many Games in Town? The Pros and Cons of Legalized Gambling,", 1973-1975 (Box-folder 58: 4)
    - Japan's energy outlook, 1974 (Box-folder 58: 5)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 58: 6)
    - Writings, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 58: 7)
    - Management Analysis Center, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 58: 8)
    - Anti-breeder nuclear reactor, 1974-1988 (Box-folder 58: 9, 59: 1-2)
    - Writings by others, 1974-2007 (Box-folder 59: 3-7, 60: 1-2)
    - Book agreements, 1974-2015 (Box-folder 60: 3-6)
    - "Implications of Technologies of Precision for Japanese Security,", 1975 July (Box-folder 60: 7)
    - Ford energy evaluation, 1975 September (Box-folder 60: 8)
    - Rowen-Lind book drafts, 1975 (Box-folder 61: 1)
    - Rowen-Deutch notes, 1975 (Box-folder 61: 2)
    - Policy Analysis, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 61: 3)
    - Stanford-Japan conference, 1976 January (Box-folder 61: 4)
    - National Institute of Education conference, 1976 April 21 (Box-folder 61: 5)
    - "Influencing the Nuclear Technology Choices of Other Countries: The Key Role of Fuel Recycling in the U. S.,", 1976 (Box-folder 61: 6)
    - Writings, 1976 (Box-folder 61: 7-8)
    - Testimony for Energy Commission, 1977 June 13 (Box-folder 61: 9)
    - "How to Develop Nuclear Power while Limiting Its Dangers: Proposed Changes in the International Nuclear System,", 1977 August 8 (Box-folder 61: 10)
    - Alumni Day speech, 1977 October 29 (Box-folder 61: 11)
    - Writings, 1977 (Box-folder 61: 12)
    - Comprehensive Energy Policy, 1977 (Box-folder 62: 1)
    - Korean Working Group, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 62: 2)
    - "The Coming Plateau in Energy Consumption," American Petroleum Institute Energy Forum, 1978 March 30 (Box-folder 62: 3)
    - Nuclear projections presentation, 1978 April 20 (Box-folder 62: 4)
    - Dealing with the International Energy Problem conference, 1978 May (Box-folder 62: 5)
    - "Nuclear Power: The Urgency to Draw Some Lines,", 1978 May (Box-folder 62: 6)
    - "Defense and the Economy," Life Officers Investment Seminar, 1978 June 12 (Box-folder 62: 7)
    - China trip, 1978 Summer (Box-folder 62: 8)
    - "Non-Proliferation Criteria for Assessing Civilian Nuclear Technologies," Argonne National Laboratory, 1978 September 29 (Box-folder 62: 9)
    - European travel, 1978 (Box-folder 62: 10)
    - Korea and Japan conferences, 1978 (Box-folder 62: 11)
    - International Scientific Forum on an Acceptable World Energy Future, 1978 (Box-folder 62: 12)
    - "Non-Proliferation: A Permanent Problem Requires a Long Term Strategy,", 1978 (Box-folder 62: 13)
    - Writings, 1978 (Box-folder 62: 14, 63: 1)
    - Iraq clippings, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 63: 2)
    - Council on Environmental Quality research, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 63: 3)
    - "An Answer to the 'So What' School,", 1979 March (Box-folder 63: 4)
      Co-authored with Albert Wohlstetter.
    - "Exploring Nuclear Futures," Bonn Conference, 1979 May 13 (Box-folder 63: 5)
    - International Association of Energy Economists - Resources for the Future, 1979 June (Box-folder 63: 6)
    - "Arms Control: Do the Costs Outweigh the Benefits?,", 1979 July 3 (Box-folder 63: 7)
    - Persian Gulf oil, 1979 July (Box-folder 63: 8)
    - "Reduce Dependence On and Increase Protection of Insecure Oil Supplies,", 1979 September (Box-folder 63: 9)
    - Committee on Energy and Natural Resources testimony, 1979 December 13 (Box-folder 63: 10)
    - The Stanford Magazine, 1979 Winter (Box-folder 64: 1)
    - U. S.-Japan Arms Control Working Group, 1979 (Box-folder 64: 2)
    - Writings, 1979 (Box-folder 64: 3)
    - Diesel Impacts Study Committee, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 64: 4)
    - Energy and National Security workshop, 1980 May (Box-folder 64: 5)
    - Overview of the Persian Gulf Report transparencies, 1980 (Box-folder 64: 6)
    - Senate Committee hearings, 1980 (Box-folder 64: 7)
    - Writings, 1980 (Box-folder 64: 8, 65: 1)
    - Viewgraph masters, circa 1980 (Box-folder 65: 2)
    - Iran-Iraq war clippings, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 65: 3)
    - Writings co-authored with John P. Weyent, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 65: 4-5)
    - Energy and the Reagan Economy talk notes, 1981 June 23 (Box-folder 65: 6)
    - Security Conference on Asia and the Pacific (SECAP) conference, 1981 (Box-folder 65: 7)
    - Writings, 1981 (Box-folder 65: 8)
    - Task Three: Scenario Analysis, circa 1981 (Box-folder 65: 9)
    - Yamal pipeline, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 65: 10)
    - Speech notes, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 65: 11)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 65: 12)
    - Hoover fellow appointments, 1983, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 13)
    - Annual activity reports, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 66: 1)
    - The Detroit News articles, 1984 July 15-16 (Box-folder 66: 2)
    - Joseph S. Berliner correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 66: 3)
    - Richard Burress correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 66: 4)
    - Albert Wohlstetter correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 66: 5)
      See also: Box/Folder 21: 3, 29: 3
    - Chronological file, 1984 (Box-folder 66: 6-7)
    - "Biting the Bullet and Other Hard Choices for Moscow,", 1984 (Box-folder 66: 8)
    - Writings, 1984 (Box-folder 66: 9)
    - Speech notes, 1984 (Box-folder 66: 10)
    - Notes, circa 1984 (Box-folder 66: 11)
    - Soviet economy, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 67: 1)
    - Soviet Working Group, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 67: 2-6)
    - Op-ed pieces, 1984-2003 (Box-folder 67: 7)
    - Harry Gelman correspondence, 1985 June (Box-folder 67: 8)
    - The American Center for Strategic Studies proposal, 1985 October 22 (Box-folder 67: 9)
    - Memoranda, 1985 (Box-folder 68: 1)
    - Eliyahu Kanovsky correspondence, 1985 (Box-folder 68: 2)
    - Speech notes, 1985 (Box-folder 68: 3)
    - European-American Institute, 1985 (Box-folder 68: 4)
    - Writings, 1985 (Box-folder 68: 5-7)
    - SECAP, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 68: 8)
    - The Making of The Future of the Soviet Empire key correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 68: 9)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 68: 10)
    - Trip to Washington, 1986 January 20 (Box-folder 68: 11)
    - Responses to Wall Street Journal article, 1986 March (Box-folder 68: 12)
    - "Gorbachev and the Ailing Russian Bear,", 1986 April (Box-folder 68: 13)
    - Soviet Leadership seminar, 1986 May (Box-folder 69: 1)
    - "How Healthy is the Bear?,", 1986 May (Box-folder 69: 2)
    - Hoover conference, 1986 July (Box-folder 69: 3)
    - Rust Professorship, 1986 September (Box-folder 69: 4)
    - International Institute for Strategic Studies, 1986 September (Box-folder 69: 5)
    - Iceland Summit memorandum, 1986 October (Box-folder 69: 6)
    - Harvard - Avoiding Nuclear War Project, 1986 November (Box-folder 69: 7)
    - "Soviet Economy and U. S. Opportunity,", 1986 December (Box-folder 69: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 69: 9)
    - SECAP, 1986 (Box-folder 69: 10)
    - National Security Affairs program, 1986 (Box-folder 69: 11)
    - Soviet Empire book notes, 1986 (Box-folder 69: 12)
    - Speech notes, 1986 (Box-folder 69: 13)
    - "Living with a Sick Bear" commentary, 1986 (Box-folder 69: 14)
    - Writings, 1986 (Box-folder 69: 15-16)
    - European American Institute for Security Research, 1986 (Box-folder 69: 17)
    - World Economic Forum, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 69: 18)
    - Annual activity reports, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 69: 19)
    - Warsaw Pact Fault Line meeting, 1987 January 26 (Box-folder 70: 1)
    - Los Angeles Times, 1987 January (Box-folder 70: 2)
    - "American Foreign Engagements: The Case for Gradualism,", 1987 January (Box-folder 70: 3)
    - SECAP policy recommendations, 1987 December (Box-folder 70: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box-folder 70: 5)
    - Memoranda, 1987 (Box-folder 70: 6)
    - Wall Street Journal, 1987 (Box-folder 70: 7)
    - New York Times, 1987 (Box-folder 70: 8)
    - Institute of American Studies - Chinese exchange, 1987 (Box-folder 70: 9)
    - Speech notes, 1987 (Box-folder 70: 10)
    - Writings, 1987 (Box-folder 70: 11-12)
    - Martin Shubik correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 70: 13)
    - Class notes, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 70: 14)
    - "American Espionage and the Soviet Target" review, 1988 September (Box-folder 70: 15)
    - Second Hoover Economic Conference, 1988 November (Box-folder 71: 1)
    - American Institute for Strategic Cooperation, 1988 December (Box-folder 71: 2)
    - "Should There be a New American International Strategy?,", 1988 December (Box-folder 71: 3)
    - Chronological file, 1988 (Box-folder 71: 4)
    - Speech notes, 1988 (Box-folder 71: 5)
    - Writings, 1988 (Box-folder 71: 6-7)
    - European American Institute - Wohlstetter, 1988 (Box-folder 71: 8)
    - SECAP, 1988 (Box-folder 71: 9)
    - Stephen M. Meyer, 1988 (Box-folder 72: 1)
    - Israel trip, 1988 (Box-folder 72: 2)
    - Turkey trip, 1988 (Box-folder 72: 3)
    - Hoover-RAND conference, 1988 (Box-folder 72: 4)
    - Soviet economy and military, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 72: 5)
    - Writings, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 72: 6)
    - Clippings on Rowen, 1988, 2005, 2015 (Box-folder 72: 7)
    - Hoover-RAND symposium on the defense sector in the Soviet economy, 1989 January (Box-folder 72: 8)
    - Speeches, 1989 (Box-folder 72: 9)
    - Chronological file, 1989 (Box-folder 72: 10)
    - Munich, Germany trip, 1989 (Box-folder 72: 11)
    - International Strategy, 1989 (Box-folder 72: 12)
    - Miscellaneous transparencies, circa 1990 (Box-folder 73: 1)
    - Travel, 1990s (Box-folder 73: 2-4)
    - International Institute for Strategic Studies, 1991 April (Box-folder 73: 5)
    - Speech notes, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 73: 6)
    - The Aspen Institute, 1991, 1993 (Box-folder 73: 7)
    - Iraq - political, 1991-2003 (Box-folder 73: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1991-2015 (Box-folder 73: 9)
    - U. S.-Japan Legislators' Committee meeting, 1992 November (Box-folder 74: 1)
    - Smith Richardson Foundation, 1992 (Box-folder 74: 2)
    - Economic Roundtable of San Francisco, 1993 January (Box-folder 74: 3)
    - Science Applications International Corporation, 1993 (Box-folder 74: 4)
    - Wall Street Journal articles written by Rowen, 1993-2009 (Box-folder 74: 5)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, 1993-2008 (Box-folder 74: 6)
    - "Inchon in the Desert,", 1994-1995 (Box-folder 74: 7)
    - Hoover conference on Congressional Accountability, 1994 February (Box-folder 74: 8)
    - CIA case study, 1994 July (Box-folder 74: 9)
    - "Scrap the SATs for Achievement Tests,", 1994 September (Box-folder 74: 10)
    - Hoover administrative materials, 1994, 1996 (Box-folder 74: 11)
    - Tenth Annual Strategy and National Security conference, 1995 June (Box-folder 74: 12)
    - "Democracy's Rising Tide,", 1995-1996 (Box-folder 74: 13)
    - A New Golden Age, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 74: 14-15)
    - "When will China become a Democracy?,", 1995-1996, 2004 (Box-folder 75: 1)
    - International environment, circa 1995 (Box-folder 75: 2)
    - Writings, 1995-2013 (Box-folder 75: 3)
    - "Adapting to the New Realities of East Asia: An American Approach,", 1996 January 7 (Box-folder 75: 4)
    - Innovation and Naval Technology conference, 1996 December (Box-folder 75: 5)
    - Research on China, 1996 (Box-folder 75: 6)
    - "A Short March,", 1996 (Box-folder 75: 7)
    - "A Short March" - back and related material, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 75: 8)
    - Political Science 125 Lecture 1, 1996, 1998 (Box-folder 75: 9)
    - Asia-Pacific Roundtable, 1996 January (Box-folder 75: 10)
    - Miscellaneous transparencies, circa 1996 (Box-folder 75: 11)
    - Hoover conference on economic reform in Korea, 1997 January (Box-folder 76: 1)
    - Clippings on China, 1997 (Box-folder 76: 2)
    - Wall Street Journal - Korea articles, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 76: 3)
    - Forbes Marshall and Indian industry, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 76: 4)
    - Rise of East Asia, 1998 April (Box-folder 76: 5)
    - India trip, 1998 June (Box-folder 76: 6)
    - Silicon Valley book, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 76: 7)
    - "The Mysteries of Silicon Valley...Unveiled,", 2000 February (Box-folder 76: 8)
    - China Reform Forum, 2000 November (Box-folder 76: 9)
    - Travel, 2000s (Box-folder 76: 10)
    - "The (Unplanned) Silicon Valley System of Innovation and Entrepreneurship,", 2001 June 21 (Box-folder 76: 11)
    - Stanford Program on Regions of Innovation and Entrepreneurship (SPRIE) research workshop, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 77: 1)
    - Chinese Research and Development research, 2001-2006 (Box-folder 77: 2)
    - International Symposium on Economic Development through Commercialization of Science and Technology, 2002 March (Box-folder 77: 3)
    - SPRIE Kyoto conference, 2002 October (Box-folder 77: 4-5)
    - Graduate School of Business manuscript, circa 2002 (Box-folder 77: 6-7, 78: 1)
    - China trip, 2003 September (Box-folder 78: 2)
    - Development of Science and Technology workshop, 2004 January (Box-folder 78: 3)
    - Taiwan trip, 2004 February (Box-folder 78: 4)
    - Industry Forum on Security Cooperation working group, 2005 January (Box-folder 78: 5)
    - Asia-Pacific Research Center, 2005 (Box-folder 78: 6)
    - "Greater China's Innovative Capacities: Progress and Challenges,", 2006 May (Box-folder 78: 7)
    - Prospectus for Science and Technology in the CIA, 2006 September (Box-folder 78: 8)
    - Stanford Project on Regions of Innovation and Entrepreneurship, 2007 March 22 (Box-folder 78: 9)
    - Stanford Institute for Economic Policy Research, 2007 (Box-folder 78: 10)
    - Notes, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 78: 11)
    - Hong Kong Innovation Project conference, 2009 January (Box-folder 78: 12)
    - Friends of St. Elizabeth Seton School, 2009-2011 (Box-folder 78: 13)
    - SPRIE conferences, 2010-2012 (Box-folder 79: 1)
    - Miscellaneous writings, undated (Box-folder 79: 2)
      Fragments and unidentified manuscripts.
    - Printed matter, 1959-2009 (Boxes 79-81)
      Comprised of published reports, journals, and scholarly magazines. Notable are issues of National Interest and Orbis with articles written by Rowen.
  - Bureau of the Budget materials, 1960-1991
    Correspondence, speeches, and writings related to Rowen's work as Assistant Director at the Bureau of the Budget, now known as the Office of Management and Budget. Rowen's work focused on developing the Planning, Programming, and Budgeting System (PPBS) aimed at analyzing and advising government budgets.
    - Speech file #3, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 82: 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 82: 3)
    - Planning, Programming, Budgeting, 1965 August - 1966 May (Box-folder 82: 4-5)
    - Chronological files, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 82: 6, 83: 1-4)
    - Bureaucracy Study Group, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 83: 5)
    - Analysis and Foreign Affairs, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 84: 1)
    - Writings by others, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 84: 2)
    - "Establishment of the Office of Economic Opportunity (OEO) Planning-Programming-Budgeting System (PPBS), 1966 July 6 (Box-folder 84: 3)
    - Bateman Work-Experience paper comments, 1966 December 28 (Box-folder 84: 4)
    - Jackson Committee Report, 1967 August 28 (Box-folder 84: 5)
    - Rowen farewell, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 84: 6)
    - Printed matter, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 84: 7-8)
      Comprised of Joint Economic Committee Prints used by Congress and "Public Finances: Needs, Sources and Utilization."
  - National Intelligence Council materials, 1976-1991
    Clippings, writings, and notes related to Rowen's term as Chairman for the National Intelligence Council.
    - Clippings on CIA investigation, 1976 (Box-folder 84: 9)
    - "Agenda for Intelligence,", 1980 November 21 (Box-folder 84: 10)
    - 1980 Embargo on U. S. grain, 1982 May 11 (Box-folder 84: 11)
    - Director of Central Intelligence meeting photo book, 1982 June 1 (Box-folder 84: 12)
    - Central Intelligence Agency briefing on the Soviet Union economy, 1982 December 1 (Box-folder 85: 1)
    - "Bestiary of Intelligence Writing,", 1982 (Box-folder 85: 2)
    - "Israel-Arab Permanent War,", 1982-1983 (Box-folder 85: 3)
    - Speech notes and Imagery annex, circa 1982 (Box-folder 85: 4)
    - European American Institute for Security Research, 1983 March (Box-folder 85: 5)
    - "An Evaluation of CIA Work on Soviet Economic Capabilities, Problems, and Prospects,", 1983 July 7 (Box-folder 85: 6)
    - Robert M. Gates, 1987, 1991 (Box-folder 85: 7)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 85: 8)
  - Photographs, 1963-2006
    - Secretary of Defense trip to Hawaii and Far East, 1990 February 10-24 (Box-folder 85: 9)
      Taken during a trip to Hawaii and the Far East with Secretary of Defense Richard "Dick" Cheney. Rowen was serving as Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs (ASD/ISA) and accompanied Cheney on the trip.
    - Blair House dinner, 1991 April 30 (Box-folder 85: 10)
      Taken during a dinner at Blair House when hosting the Japanese Minister of Defense, Yukihiko Ikeda.
    - Full Honors luncheon, 1990 November 14 (Box-folder 85: 11)
      Taken during a Full Honors luncheon at the Pentagon. The luncheon was in honor of the Korean Minister of National Defense, Lee Jong Koo.
    - Hosted award ceremony, 1991 July 31 (Box-folder 85: 12)
      Henry and Beverly Rowen with Richard "Dick" Cheney at an award ceremony in Henry Rowen's honor.
    - Portraits, undated (Box-folder 85: 13)
      Portraits of Rowen from various dates.
    - Senior Seminar, 1968 January 25 (Box-folder 85: 14)
      Ambassador G. Lewis Jones, Henry S. Rowen, and Jeffrey C. Kitchen at the Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy at the Foreign Service Institute.
    - Honor cordon and meeting, 1991 March 1 (Box-folder 85: 15)
      Taken during an honor cordon and meeting with the Filipino Minister of Foreign Affairs, Raul Manglapus.
    - White House visit, 2006 April 21 (Box-folder 85: 16)
      Large group visiting President George W. Bush.
    - North Atlantic Council, 1963 (Box-folder 85: 17)
      Photograph and letter from Admiral Smith of Rowen visiting with the North Atlantic Council to Norfolk.
    - International Symposium on Economic Development through Commercialization of Science and Technology, 2002 March 19-22 (Box-folder 85: 18)
      Rowen and other symposium participants.
    - Assistant Director Rowen, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 85: 19)
      Rowen at work as Assistant Director of the Bureau of the Budget.
    - Distinguished Public Service Award, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 87: 1)
      Mounted photograph of Rowen holding his award with Admiral Thomas B. Hayward. A handwritten note from Admiral Hayward is included at the bottom.
    - Strategic Air Command, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 87: 2)
      Mounted photograph of Rowen with General John T. Chain Jr. of Strategic Air Command.